You don't need to do a completely novel analysis or use brand new data to
differentiate your data. Science projects. Sometimes a great
story will do as much, if not more than these things to get
you noticed. Rather than just jumping straight into an analysis,
think about who the analysis analysis is for. Working with the Titanic
data set has completely different meaning. You're analyzing it
to understand the risk. For an insurance company looking to
cover another large ship. An analysis of the Irish dataset comes to life
if your customer is the largest flower shop in New York City who's trying
to reduce their costs by identifying pickable flowers with machine
learning. These are some of the most boring and common projects you can do,
but they've become exciting by envisioning the customer and the
story associated with them. If you want to stand out, add these elements to
your projects and talk about them in story form on your resume and
in your interviews. This is a short video, so do me a favor and watch
it again. While you're watching, think about who the target of your most recent project
is and how you could tell a great story around that project.