Data science is a bit of a buzzword and a hot topic in tech
these days. As a practicing data scientist, I figured I'd explain
what the field is. In this short, to spice things up,
I will be explaining what the field is after after I eat one of
these. Habaneros,
I forgot this.
Okay, the most basic level data science
is problem solving. It's a multidisciplinary
approach to problem solving. So we borrow from the field of computer
science, from statistics and from business.
A typical problem would be to predict if
someone will buy your products after visiting
your website site. If you want to learn more about data science, machine learning,
artificial intelligence, check out my YouTube channel,
part of some fun project videos. I also have a lot of live
content about how to break into the field. I massively regret.